<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.2000class.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.2000class.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_GB" /><updated>2021-01-18T08:19:51-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">2000 Class Association</title><subtitle>The 2000 Class Association is the official association for the 2000 sailing  dinghy. The 2000, previously known as the Laser 2000, is an entry-level  performance assymmetric sailing dinghy. The boat is sailed by serious racers and families alike.
</subtitle><author><name>2000 Class Association</name></author><entry><title type="html">18 Jan 2021 Facebook chat about jib cleat positions ……..</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/18/18-jan-2021-facebook-chat-about-jib-cleat-positions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="18 Jan 2021 Facebook chat about jib cleat positions …….." /><published>2021-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/18/18-jan-2021-facebook-chat-about-jib-cleat-positions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/18/18-jan-2021-facebook-chat-about-jib-cleat-positions/">&lt;p&gt;A member is asking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am after some tech advice re changing my jib sheet cleats and riser wedges. The old class website has a tech blog, but I do not appear to be able to find it. Does it still exist? If not can anyone advise on best cleat / wedge set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently have Holt Allen 676 cleats with a HA 893 wedge which I believes gives a 7 Degree lift. (I believe original set up on 22235). I am looking at Harken 150 cleats with a 15 degree wedge part nos H294. Is this the way to go to keep my crew happy to cleat off easier esp when out hiking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/joe.gallivan.12?comment_id=Y29tbWVudDo1NTc3MjczMTk4OTU3MTQzXzU1NzczNjAxNzg5NDg0NDU%3D&amp;amp;__cft__\[0\]=AZUXm_yM14vjO49PA7PCwRb1e4jInIBIGZTf7FQq_19dH-HS50glU97Ot59h0FgBS99I8xrc4-V1OAG0fqzkRjDnSNJop7Fv6L6mKdtD4KwDOpyCH7q6-WI52znBPwQWiw8CFjwCDyKArKGIS0bMSJCkD8BEWzX9Pl-wQoPwFpfMlA&amp;amp;__tn__=R\]-R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joe Gallivan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with what Chris has said, the cleat height is all down to the crews preference and technique. The higher the cleat is angled, the easier the crew will be able to uncleat it. the downside to this is that it can be harder to uncleat it when hiking. A good angled would be to run the sheet across the boat to the windward side in the gunwale and the sheet perfectly cleated. This mean it wont wake much for the crew to cuncleat it in maneuver or gust but easy enough to cleat normally or with the outside of the foot on-top of the sheet. Hard to explain by text but I hope you get the gist of what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/2000classassociation/?comment_id=Y29tbWVudDo1NTc3MjczMTk4OTU3MTQzXzU1Nzc0NTIwNDg5MzkyNTg%3D&amp;amp;__cft__\[0\]=AZUXm_yM14vjO49PA7PCwRb1e4jInIBIGZTf7FQq_19dH-HS50glU97Ot59h0FgBS99I8xrc4-V1OAG0fqzkRjDnSNJop7Fv6L6mKdtD4KwDOpyCH7q6-WI52znBPwQWiw8CFjwCDyKArKGIS0bMSJCkD8BEWzX9Pl-wQoPwFpfMlA&amp;amp;__tn__=R\]-R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000 Class Association&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the cleat too low is blinking awkward. Having the cleat too high is down right dangerous! Not being able to uncleat when you need to means the crew wont have the confidence to pull the jib in tight and cleat it when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Jordan:&lt;/strong&gt; One of my articles from 10 or 12 years ago for the Millennium Mutterings said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jib sheet cleats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the angle of the cleats correct: Laser seem to expect the crew to be sitting sedately on the thwart, not sitting out next to the shrouds. You will need to swing the cleats forward to allow them to be jammed easily when the crew is sitting out next to the shrouds. Also, you need to adjust them up and down (either with wedges under the cleats, or a big pair of mole grips and bend the plate) to ensure the crew can both jamb the jib, AND release it quickly when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fore-aft position of the cleats: some people say they should be further back in strong winds, to allow the slot to open up automatically. Others say that raking the mast back a little will achieve the same effect. Both are correct: but we just leave them in the same position (one hole forward from right at the back) for all weathers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have just upgraded to the harken 150 with the 15 degree wedge. Find it works well for us. Like everyone is saying though it is what works best for you as not being able to uncleat is a real possibility with too much upwards angle. Biggest improvement we found was angling the cleats forward as Chris says, when we bought ours they were angled to face the thwart which was the main challenge for getting the jib cleated when at the shroud.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>2000 Sailors various...</name></author><summary type="html">A member is asking:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thorney island SC :: West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series Round 4 date change</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/13/thorney-island-sc-west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-round-4-date-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thorney island SC :: West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series Round 4 date change" /><published>2021-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/13/thorney-island-sc-west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-round-4-date-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/13/thorney-island-sc-west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-round-4-date-change/">&lt;p&gt;Millennium Series 4 - Thorney Island SC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13th January 2021 ::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies to all those who have booked time in their 2021 calendar, but we have had to change the date of the Thorney Island SC Millennium event&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OLD DATE            10 - 11 July&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEW DATE            24 -25 July&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change is due to a clash with another local event that would have created issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rob Burridge, 2000 Class Sailing Secretary  </name></author><summary type="html">Millennium Series 4 - Thorney Island SC.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Nationals FREE ENTRY draw time limit extended to 28 February !</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/11/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Nationals FREE ENTRY draw time limit extended to 28 February !" /><published>2021-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/11/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/11/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february/">&lt;p&gt;Due to Lockdown 3 we’re extending the time limit for entries to the Nationals to be entered into the draw for a FREE ENTRY !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what you have to do is enter and pay £40 by Sunday 28th February 2021. On 1st March - around lunchtime - a draw will be made and the winner gets an entry to the 2021 Nationals and their £40 refunded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to the Nationals at the excellent Royal Torbay Yacht Club in Torquay is certainly one the of surest ways you can have fun in 2021 , so don’t delay getting your entry in - in an average year we’d expect 50+ boats to enter; in the face of car ferry jams, limits on places to go abroad for your holidays thanks to covid, and the testing procedures that you may have to undergo and the expense of those tests, we’re expecting a high number to opt to stay in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind also that as one of the few dinghy classes to run a proper championship and open meetings in 2020 there’s been a steady upturn in people looking to acquire their first 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter now and get something in your diary you can start to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kev.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien, 2000 Class chair. </name></author><summary type="html">Due to Lockdown 3 we’re extending the time limit for entries to the Nationals to be entered into the draw for a FREE ENTRY !</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Nationals FREE ENTRY draw time limit extended to 28 February !</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/10/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Nationals FREE ENTRY draw time limit extended to 28 February !" /><published>2021-01-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/10/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/10/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Due to Lockdown 3 we’re extending the time limit for entries to the Nationals to be entered into the draw for a FREE ENTRY !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;So what you have to do is enter and pay £40 by Sunday 28th February 2021. On 1st March - around lunchtime - a draw will be made and the winner gets an entry to the 2021 Nationals and their £40 refunded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Going to the Nationals at the excellent Royal Torbay Yacht Club in Torquay is certainly one the of surest ways you can have fun in 2021 , so don’t delay getting your entry in - in an average year we’d expect 50+ boats to enter; in the face of car ferry jams, limits on places to go abroad for your holidays thanks to covid, and the testing procedures that you may have to undergo and the expense of those tests, we’re expecting a high number to opt to stay in the UK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bear in mind also that as one of the few dinghy classes to run a proper championship and open meetings in 2020 there’s been a steady upturn in people looking to acquire their first 2000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter now and get something in your diary you can start to look forward to!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien, 2000 Class chair. </name></author><summary type="html">Due to Lockdown 3 we’re extending the time limit for entries to the Nationals to be entered into the draw for a FREE ENTRY !</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Noble Marine Insurance renew their sponsorship for 2021</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/09/noble-marine-insurance-renew-their-sponsorship-for-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Noble Marine Insurance renew their sponsorship for 2021" /><published>2021-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/09/noble-marine-insurance-renew-their-sponsorship-for-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/09/noble-marine-insurance-renew-their-sponsorship-for-2021/">&lt;p&gt;We’re extremely pleased to announce that  Noble Marine Insurance have renewed their sponsorship of the 2000 Class for 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noble have been impressed by the manner in which we can put their insurance expertise in front of our 280 + members by our Fast News emails, the 600 to 2000 people who regularly see our social media activity on Facebook and Instagram, the 70 + 2000 Fleet Captains at sailing clubs all over the 4 nations of the UK who can reach their 2000 club sailors, many of whom are not yet class association members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2000 Class sailors have always found insuring with Noble to be a truly painless experience; their premiums are usually the best and they give our members a very useful discount in addition. Noble’s claims handling is friendly , professional, quick and even sympathetic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noblemarine.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.noblemarine.co.uk/&quot;&gt;https://www.noblemarine.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/01/09/20190813_193654.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brace of Lauras toast Noble Marine Insurance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura Holmes - Short (L) &amp;amp;  Laura Barnham (R)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien, 2000 Class chair. </name></author><summary type="html">We’re extremely pleased to announce that Noble Marine Insurance have renewed their sponsorship of the 2000 Class for 2021.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are your sail numbers displayed legally?</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/02/are-your-sail-numbers-displayed-legally/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are your sail numbers displayed legally?" /><published>2021-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/02/are-your-sail-numbers-displayed-legally</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/02/are-your-sail-numbers-displayed-legally/">&lt;p&gt;Sail Numbers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear 2000 sailors, my name is John Best. I have been the technical Officer for the class for the last couple of years since my predecessor Richard decided to step over to the dark side and now sails a 400, quite successfully as I understand it. I have been messing about in boats since I was 8 which seems to be 64 years. 18 years ago I bought an RS 800, as my first asymmetric racing dinghy, then 15 years ago I bought 2000 2248, which made much more sense, and immediately disappeared to a SW France lake to sail it. It all came as a bit of a shock when I returned to the UK about 3 years ago, towing my trusty 2000 Mercury Rising behind me, and straight away sailed in the Castle Combe Nationals, only for two days and I had some new sails delivered to me at Castle Combe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked with complex sailing rules in various classes and about 22 years ago suddenly found myself in the role of an ISAF class measurer for Dragon’s and Flying Dutchman, both these classes are from the past but are still sailed all around the World. I do have some understanding of the closed class rules of the 2000 class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a much younger partner in crime, named Joe Gallivan, a young but experienced dinghy sailor, who came up through the Laser, RS Aero, RS 800, and latterly RS 700, he is in the market for a 2000, but has a great understanding of closed class rules and has agreed to cuff me round the ear if I behave badly with class rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are producing a series of articles about the 2000 rules, and we are going to start with Sail Numbers on the Mainsail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Too easy”, I hear you cry , I shan’t even need to read it , however, we have photographic evidence that about 25% of racing 2000’s have incorrectly laid out and stuck on sail numbers. “Why should I care” I hear you cry, but since I became the class technical chap two years ago, I have made a habit of talking to the Race Officers at the Nationals in Torquay and Tenby and they both said, “why haven’t all the boats got their numbers in the same place on their mainsails”! I wasn’t at the Brixham Nationals, put together by some very determined class members and Brixham Yacht Club, but the Race Officer there said much the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the closed rules are pretty specific about where the numbers should be, and we, Joe and I will gently remind you. If you haven’t already got a set of the 2000 class rules, there is a wealth of information in there, including what to do with sail numbers on your shiny new mainsail. The diagram, which is pretty self-explanatory can be found on page 4 of the measurement rules and was last edited in April 2019, so pretty recently! If you don’t feel the need to download the rules, or at least read them, ask yourself a question, “would I drive a vehicle without a perusal of the Highway Code”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/01/02/sail-number-measurement-rules.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sail numbers are an important part of a dinghy while racing due to being the easiest way of identifying a boat while out on the water. When racing is such big fleets (30+ boats) it can be difficult to spot when a boat is over the line and sail numbers helps them to be recorded for a disqualification. If the race officer or any of the race management cannot read the sail numbers due to incorrect fitting or placement, then this may give that competitor an unfair advantage and could lead to protests or even disqualification from the event for not complying with the class rules. These things are all avoided by making sure you sail, and boat comply with these rules to make sure the racing is fair between all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers should obviously be on the mainsail, starting or finishing 76 mm from the leech tape, each number should be 66 mm from the next one to it, and the numbers should be laid parallel to and 76 mm above or below the second mainsail batten, counting up from the mainsail foot. Starboard side numbers above the batten pocket and Port side numbers below it. When your shiny new mainsail turns up, and it may well be Charcoal coloured, you’ll know what to do, and the class has decided to stick with black numbers for the new mainsail fabric. We have included in the article the class rules page on sail numbers with diagrams on how they should be done correctly and also a photo of how they should look on a sail done correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/01/02/correct-sail-numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may not be aware of RS Boats and Hyde Sails decision, after consultation with us, the class managers, to not produce anymore white Aramid sailcloth, because it turns out that we are the only class using it, and are running out of it, when I spoke with Hyde sails after the first lockdown, they thought that they had enough for 8 more mainsails! They sold me the new concept by saying that only making about 2000 linear metres of white cloth would hike the price of the cloth by about 45%! Thus, we will soon be using a black see-through aramid shiny new material for mainsails, which my crew thinks is quite sexy, and a bit OO7ish! Amazingly enough the black sail numbers work quite well on it, better even than white ones, go figure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I actually find the black cloth easier to read! As another aside, if anybody has any queries about this new cloth or other measurement questions, we will, with the assistance of the class internet guru’s, attempt to set up an internet assistance address for rule queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to email us with any questions and wanting advice on anything 2000 based, our email address is &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tech@2000class.org&quot;&gt;tech@2000class.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Best and Joe Gallivan, Technical Chappies&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John Best &amp; Joe Gallivan , Technical Officers </name></author><summary type="html">Sail Numbers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series 2021 sponsorship details announced.</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2020/12/21/west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-2021-sponsorship-details-announced/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series 2021 sponsorship details announced." /><published>2020-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2020/12/21/west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-2021-sponsorship-details-announced</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2020/12/21/west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-2021-sponsorship-details-announced/">&lt;p&gt;Title Sponsor announced for the 2000 Class Millennium Series in 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;West Country Boat Repairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2000 Class have engaged with West Country Boat Repairs as their title sponsor for the 6 rounds of the Millennium Series in 2021. The Series will be 2 inland events and 4 sea rounds all in spectacular locations from Derbyshire in April down to Hampshire from April to September. In keeping with the ethos of the 2000s as friendly and serious racing in a boat that has everything the keen racer wants yet isn’t intimidating to the less experienced sailor, the programme next year gives opportunities for first time Open Event travellers at a large range of locations and in conditions likely to be manageable for the family sailors and sometimes challenging for the proficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“West Country Boat Repairs are delighted to be sponsoring the prestigious Millennium Series in 2021. We will be supplying a range of prizes including places on our Dinghy Repair workshops, a full 2000 refurbishment and plenty of our famous Ugly Mugs. We will have spot prizes as well as prizes for the overall winners, so there is a chance for everyone, whatever your level. We already know many of the 2000 sailors as valued customers and look forward to meeting the rest of the fleet during 2021. We know that there’s going to be at least one of the events that suits your location and experience so come and join in the fun; you may go home with a prize!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Millennium Series was taken in 2019 and 2020 by Simon Horsfield and Katie Burridge, the Sail Juice 2019 - 20 winners who’ve made a great start in the 20 -21 series, so the Millennium Series proves to be a great place to learn how to mix it with the top sailors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prizes available from West Country Boat Repairs include boat and foils overhauls, and days on WCBR’s boat repair courses at their workshops in Gloucestershire. There are also places on racing sailing training courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a great fit for the 2000 Class “said Mark Foley, 2000 Publicity Officer. “We are constantly dealing with people asking us where they can get their hands on a 2000, as they are snapped up when they come up for sale. So what better way to look after your boat’s resale value than get an upgrade courtesy of WCBR, or spend a day on a course learning how to keep your boat in tip top condition by yourself? Indeed, if you are not in the position to get a new boat from RS Sailing, when you see a boat for sale that needs some work, put yourself in touch with WCBR beforehand and have a chat about what the improvements you want might cost before you negotiate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below: Mark Foley 2000 Class publicity &amp;amp; Pete Vincent of West Country Boat Repairs, enjoying one of their boat repair courses in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/12/25/2020-06-23_6546.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Foley, 2000 Class publicity.  </name></author><summary type="html">Title Sponsor announced for the 2000 Class Millennium Series in 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Events Programme published</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2020/11/30/2021-events-programme-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Events Programme published" /><published>2020-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2020/11/30/2021-events-programme-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2020/11/30/2021-events-programme-published/">&lt;p&gt;Rob Burridge has finalised the 2021 events programme encompassing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Millennium Open Series&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Northern Series&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Coached Open meetings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*National Championships&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All events are now detailed on the Events page. Check them out and start pencilling in the ones you want to do, assuming you can’t make them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/11/30/_dsc8247-edit-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Foley </name></author><summary type="html">Rob Burridge has finalised the 2021 events programme encompassing</summary></entry></feed>