<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.2000class.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.2000class.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_GB" /><updated>2021-03-02T13:40:37-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">2000 Class Association</title><subtitle>The 2000 Class Association is the official association for the 2000 sailing  dinghy. The 2000, previously known as the Laser 2000, is an entry-level  performance assymmetric sailing dinghy. The boat is sailed by serious racers and families alike.
</subtitle><author><name>2000 Class Association</name></author><entry><title type="html">Static rig set up : base settings.</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/02/03/static-rig-set-up-base-settings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Static rig set up : base settings." /><published>2021-02-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/02/03/static-rig-set-up-base-settings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/02/03/static-rig-set-up-base-settings/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mast Heel Position&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is measured from the back of the mast to dead top centre of the transom as pictured. The measurement is 2720mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shroud T Terminal Housing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure the shroud T terminals are in the bottom holes as pictured, the higher holes are for the optional Trapezing kit wires (trapezing isn’t permitted for racing)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spreader Length and Angle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreader length: Measured tip to tip to the centre of the shroud wire, the measurement is 860mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Spreader Angle: Measured from the mast track to the whipping twine as pictured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;The whipping twine is simply tied onto the shrouds and pulled tight and is just there for the purpose of measuring remove it after measuring. The measurement is between 170 - 180 mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TO SET THE BOAT UP YOU MUST PUT JIB UP WITH THE CORRECT RIG TENSION ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rig Tension&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measured at shoulder height on the shroud using a rig tension meter 330lbs or 150kg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/loos-gauge.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halyard Datum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, tie the halyard to a long tape measure (it needs to longer then 7m) using the bobble method. Raise the halyard up to the top of the mast, then tension the halyard ensuring it is at the top. Now read the tape measure off at the goose neck it should read 5. 23m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do this every time before we measure the mast rake to ensure the halyard is in the same place every time. Put simply, it ensures consistency every time we pull the halyard up. If it measures 5.23m we know we have the correct starting point before then measuring the mast rake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mast Rake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having checked the halyard datum, swing the tape measure to back of the boat and read off the number it should read 6560mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top tip avoid trying this in 25 knots of breeze as reading the numbers accurately is challenging!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjustment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If having done all the above correctly, you might not have the correct measurement of 6560mm, If this is the case then you will need to adjust the shroud clevis pins up or down on the chain plates (pictured below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/02/03/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjustment example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hole up or down is equal to 40mm + / -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hole diagonally up or down is equal to 20mm + /-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the above adjustments, you will be a achieve the base measurement of 6560mm, if you can’t re trace your steps to chance the potential error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Horsfield Coaching&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;www.simonhorsfieldcoaching.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Simon Horsfield</name></author><summary type="html">Mast Heel Position</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2000 Class Newcomers Top Tips - tuning</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/22/2000-class-newcomers-top-tips-preparation-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2000 Class Newcomers Top Tips - tuning" /><published>2021-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/22/2000-class-newcomers-top-tips-preparation-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/22/2000-class-newcomers-top-tips-preparation-1/">&lt;p&gt;We are super excited that the 2021 National Championships will have a specific ‘First Timer Championship’ aimed at those who are new to championship racing and have never competed as a helm in a class National championships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be an upper wind speed limit and results will be extracted from the National event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We realise how daunting this may be, and we’ve all been there, so we wanted to put some hints and tips together to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve written these as a team so will hopefully give some perspective from both ends of the boat. Please don’t be afraid to ask us questions, we are always happy to help. Happy sailing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuning/Boat set up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuning a dinghy can be a little daunting and complicated, thankfully it’s pretty straight forward in the 2000. My advice with tuning is to set the boat up with a solid set of base settings, then simply forget about tuning. It’s more important to be able to sail the boat effectively through the wind range. Ask yourself some tough questions, can you tack and gybe without losing speed, are you capsizing at the corners, how is your starting and mark rounding, and is your boat handling crisp? If the answer is no to any of the above, it would be far more effective to develop these skills in the first instance. How often do you hear people in the dinghy park or bar saying “well if I had adjusted this or raked back we would have done so much better”… They possibly failed to mention the fact that they capsized, or filled the boat up with water during a tack!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In sailing we need a constant because we seldom, if ever, get one. The wind, and the sea state, etc. are always different so there are many variables! If you leave the tuning alone, at least you have one constant and with that we can focus on the fundamental thing which is to sail the boat effectively through the wind range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So set up your boat up, leave it, sail with a purpose and practice the fundamentals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the settings I used for over 10 years - you don’t have use them of course, but it’s a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreader Length and Angle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spreaders should be 860mm long (tip to tip)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the deflection to 170mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mast Heel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is critical for pointing and balance of the rig. In the 2000, measure from the back of the mast to the back of the rudder post. It should read 2720mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rig Tension&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is measured on the port shroud, using the 3mm scale on a loos gauge. A good starting point is to put 150kg or 330lbs of tension on the rig - this is 24 when reading from a loos gauge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mast Rake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is measured from the top of the mast to the top of the rudder post. Ensure the Jib is up and the rig tension is set (24 loos gauge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, measure your datum: hoist the halyard to the top of the mast and pull it tight. Measure to the gooseneck which should be close to 5220mm. Why? Well this gives you a constant, ensuring the tape measure is pulled to the top and at the same place each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swing the tape aft to the rudder post and it should read 6560mm. To adjust the rig, you can simply move the shroud pins up or down. If you move up or down a hole it makes 40mm + / - and if you adjust diagonally up or down it makes 20mm + /- difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the golden rule: each time you adjust the shroud pins, you must recheck the rig tension and set it to 24 on the loos gauge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upwind Boat Speed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about speed, I often take it back to basics to think about what I can improve. The main things to think about for upwind boat speed in the 2000 are the 5 essentials, and how we can use these effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance: sounds so simple but something we can all overlook. Ever looked back on a photo from an event where you thought you sailed the boat flat, but in reality were quite far off?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In strong winds, this requires a lot of hiking and playing the mainsheet. Make sure you have enough kicker on to enable you to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light winds, the crew carefully positions their bodyweight so the helm can continue to sit on the windward side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trim: super important in the 2000, as its a relatively heavy boat. In light winds, aim to be as far forwards as possible; I sit against the shroud and helm should be as far forwards as possible, whilst still lightly holding the tiller extension. Remember this straight out of a roll tack, something often forgotten as the helm must step back out of the front cockpit during the manoeuvre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high winds helm and crew should sit together, shoulder to shoulder as combined bodyweight makes the most impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sail Settings: whilst ashore, take the time to see how sheeting your sails in and out 1/2/3 inches affects the sail shape. It might be more than you think. Remember this and use the flecks and colours in the sheets to help; if the wind drops, easing as little as ‘one fleck’ on the jib sheet can make a huge difference in reducing the stalling of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 2000, sail settings are most important in light to medium conditions where the boat can easily stall. Playing the sheets as you move your bodyweight is the most important thing e.g. practice this enough times so that if the wind eases, as you move in, you instinctively ease the jib sheet at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Down Wind Speed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 sail downwind blasting is surely what sailing is all about; sadly it’s not always champagne sailing conditions! How do we sail effectively in the 2000 downwind? Well firstly we must understand CMG vs. VMG. CMG is (Course Made Good) the shortest route to the leeward mark, whilst VMG is (Velocity Made Good) sailing at the most efficient speed downwind relative to the wind speed whilst making the best progress to the leeward mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modes of sailing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 3 modes of sailing downwind; Displacement, Semi Apparent, and Full Apparent. The skill is in knowing which technique to use and when. Unfortunately I can’t tell you which works as this comes down to crew weight, waves, and experience at knowing when to switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at each in turn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Displacement:&lt;/strong&gt; In winds of 10 knots or less, sail the shortest course to the leeward mark. The 2000 is underpowered and as a result, sailing high for speed doesn’t pay as the boat is simply too slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top tips:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weight forwards to the shrouds, crew and helm opposite one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crew calls pressure or no pressure in the spinnaker sheet, the helm sails as low as possible listening to the crew’s calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider raising the centreboard slightly - this allows the boat to slide to leeward. Be warned this makes the boat very unstable and the spinnaker will collapse easily as there is less resistance to help it fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semi Apparent:&lt;/strong&gt; 11- 16 knots is planing in the gusts and soaking (sailing low) in the lulls. The aim is to get the boat planing whilst not sailing too high. It’s really tricky if I am honest, and extremely frustrating as light crews can sail slightly higher and faster whilst heavier crews have to sail lower and slower. The aim is always to sail low in the gusts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top tips:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crew sits in the front cockpit or slightly to windward so as to sail the boat flat with bodyweight midships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raise the centreboard half up – this allows some slide but also some stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear away in the gusts to sail as low as possible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In waves, sail at an angle that matches the wave speed – this will require practice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full apparent:&lt;/strong&gt; 17 – 30 knots, send it!!! In champagne conditions, sail high. The crew and helm sit to windward. Build up apparent wind and bear away in the gusts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top Tips:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sail with slight leeward heel to stop the boat rolling on top of you and keep weight aft to balance the boat further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear away in the gusts – ‘go with the gust’!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gybe at maximum speed! If you lose speed going into the gybe, don’t gybe - instead increase speed and try again (alternatively swim!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep the centreboard down or take some brave pills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stress Free Starting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to a stress free start is to stay out of trouble. How do you stay out of trouble, and what does that even mean? It means being in control and creating space to start without infringing rules or coming together with other boats. It means you can start your race cleanly, in the right frame of mind, as well as having options up the first beat e.g. to tack off or to use your speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you achieve this? PRACTICE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practice holding position on the line on Starboard, this is your safest position. Practice with no other boats around. Choose a buoy, take a transit and sit there for as long as you can. This does take some boat handling skill, but doing it over and over again will improve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, practice with other boats around. Aim to slow down on the line, as above, and observe boats coming in above and below and keep your space on the line. Boats coming in below you have right of way and you must be prepared for this by anticipating. You do not want to be stuck head to wind, with no power or option to accelerate when this happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also attend events before the nationals, or go club racing, and get used to other boats being on the line. Observe where they set themselves up. When you get into a situation where you start to feel stressed or out of control, learn from that. Sometimes it’s only by experiencing a situation that you can learn from it and avoid being in that situation again. This simply comes from practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know what the starting sequence is and what the flags mean. The 2021 Nationals are likely to be run under the standard RRS rules, 5-4-1-go. However, I study the Sailing Instructions before every event, as this might not be the case! Understand what the flags mean, and if you’re unsure just ask someone, but do this before going on the water. The more unexpected events you can remove, the more comfortable you will feel on the start line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common preparatory signal flags are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flag P (Blue with a White Square) - effectively the ‘no penalty’ signal. Boats can ‘dip’ back over the start line if over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flag I (Yellow with a Black Circle) - Boats on course side in the minute before the start must return to the pre-course side of the line &lt;strong&gt;around either end of the line.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘Black’ Flag – Boats on course side in the minute before the start are, without a hearing, BFD (Black Flag Disqualified)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flag U (Red and White Chequered) - Whilst not in RRS the Sailing Instructions can amend the rules to include other flags. U is essentially the same as a black flag except that after a general recall or abandonment after the start, the slate is wiped clean and boats who were over can join in the next race.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Simon Horsfield and Katie Burridge</name></author><summary type="html">We are super excited that the 2021 National Championships will have a specific ‘First Timer Championship’ aimed at those who are new to championship racing and have never competed as a helm in a class National championships.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">18 Jan 2021 Facebook chat about jib cleat positions ……..</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/18/18-jan-2021-facebook-chat-about-jib-cleat-positions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="18 Jan 2021 Facebook chat about jib cleat positions …….." /><published>2021-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/18/18-jan-2021-facebook-chat-about-jib-cleat-positions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/18/18-jan-2021-facebook-chat-about-jib-cleat-positions/">&lt;p&gt;A member is asking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am after some tech advice re changing my jib sheet cleats and riser wedges. The old class website has a tech blog, but I do not appear to be able to find it. Does it still exist? If not can anyone advise on best cleat / wedge set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently have Holt Allen 676 cleats with a HA 893 wedge which I believes gives a 7 Degree lift. (I believe original set up on 22235). I am looking at Harken 150 cleats with a 15 degree wedge part nos H294. Is this the way to go to keep my crew happy to cleat off easier esp when out hiking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/joe.gallivan.12?comment_id=Y29tbWVudDo1NTc3MjczMTk4OTU3MTQzXzU1NzczNjAxNzg5NDg0NDU%3D&amp;amp;__cft__\[0\]=AZUXm_yM14vjO49PA7PCwRb1e4jInIBIGZTf7FQq_19dH-HS50glU97Ot59h0FgBS99I8xrc4-V1OAG0fqzkRjDnSNJop7Fv6L6mKdtD4KwDOpyCH7q6-WI52znBPwQWiw8CFjwCDyKArKGIS0bMSJCkD8BEWzX9Pl-wQoPwFpfMlA&amp;amp;__tn__=R\]-R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joe Gallivan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with what Chris has said, the cleat height is all down to the crews preference and technique. The higher the cleat is angled, the easier the crew will be able to uncleat it. the downside to this is that it can be harder to uncleat it when hiking. A good angled would be to run the sheet across the boat to the windward side in the gunwale and the sheet perfectly cleated. This mean it wont wake much for the crew to cuncleat it in maneuver or gust but easy enough to cleat normally or with the outside of the foot on-top of the sheet. Hard to explain by text but I hope you get the gist of what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/2000classassociation/?comment_id=Y29tbWVudDo1NTc3MjczMTk4OTU3MTQzXzU1Nzc0NTIwNDg5MzkyNTg%3D&amp;amp;__cft__\[0\]=AZUXm_yM14vjO49PA7PCwRb1e4jInIBIGZTf7FQq_19dH-HS50glU97Ot59h0FgBS99I8xrc4-V1OAG0fqzkRjDnSNJop7Fv6L6mKdtD4KwDOpyCH7q6-WI52znBPwQWiw8CFjwCDyKArKGIS0bMSJCkD8BEWzX9Pl-wQoPwFpfMlA&amp;amp;__tn__=R\]-R&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000 Class Association&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the cleat too low is blinking awkward. Having the cleat too high is down right dangerous! Not being able to uncleat when you need to means the crew wont have the confidence to pull the jib in tight and cleat it when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Jordan:&lt;/strong&gt; One of my articles from 10 or 12 years ago for the Millennium Mutterings said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jib sheet cleats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the angle of the cleats correct: Laser seem to expect the crew to be sitting sedately on the thwart, not sitting out next to the shrouds. You will need to swing the cleats forward to allow them to be jammed easily when the crew is sitting out next to the shrouds. Also, you need to adjust them up and down (either with wedges under the cleats, or a big pair of mole grips and bend the plate) to ensure the crew can both jamb the jib, AND release it quickly when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fore-aft position of the cleats: some people say they should be further back in strong winds, to allow the slot to open up automatically. Others say that raking the mast back a little will achieve the same effect. Both are correct: but we just leave them in the same position (one hole forward from right at the back) for all weathers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have just upgraded to the harken 150 with the 15 degree wedge. Find it works well for us. Like everyone is saying though it is what works best for you as not being able to uncleat is a real possibility with too much upwards angle. Biggest improvement we found was angling the cleats forward as Chris says, when we bought ours they were angled to face the thwart which was the main challenge for getting the jib cleated when at the shroud.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>2000 Sailors various...</name></author><summary type="html">A member is asking:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thorney island SC :: West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series Round 4 date change</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/13/thorney-island-sc-west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-round-4-date-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thorney island SC :: West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series Round 4 date change" /><published>2021-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/13/thorney-island-sc-west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-round-4-date-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/13/thorney-island-sc-west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-round-4-date-change/">&lt;p&gt;Millennium Series 4 - Thorney Island SC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13th January 2021 ::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies to all those who have booked time in their 2021 calendar, but we have had to change the date of the Thorney Island SC Millennium event&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OLD DATE            10 - 11 July&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEW DATE            24 -25 July&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change is due to a clash with another local event that would have created issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rob Burridge, 2000 Class Sailing Secretary  </name></author><summary type="html">Millennium Series 4 - Thorney Island SC.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Nationals FREE ENTRY draw time limit extended to 28 February !</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/10/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Nationals FREE ENTRY draw time limit extended to 28 February !" /><published>2021-01-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/10/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/10/2021-nationals-free-entry-draw-time-limit-extended-to-28-february/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Due to Lockdown 3 we’re extending the time limit for entries to the Nationals to be entered into the draw for a FREE ENTRY !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;So what you have to do is enter and pay £40 by Sunday 28th February 2021. On 1st March - around lunchtime - a draw will be made and the winner gets an entry to the 2021 Nationals and their £40 refunded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Going to the Nationals at the excellent Royal Torbay Yacht Club in Torquay is certainly one the of surest ways you can have fun in 2021 , so don’t delay getting your entry in - in an average year we’d expect 50+ boats to enter; in the face of car ferry jams, limits on places to go abroad for your holidays thanks to covid, and the testing procedures that you may have to undergo and the expense of those tests, we’re expecting a high number to opt to stay in the UK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bear in mind also that as one of the few dinghy classes to run a proper championship and open meetings in 2020 there’s been a steady upturn in people looking to acquire their first 2000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter now and get something in your diary you can start to look forward to!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien, 2000 Class chair. </name></author><summary type="html">Due to Lockdown 3 we’re extending the time limit for entries to the Nationals to be entered into the draw for a FREE ENTRY !</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Noble Marine Insurance renew their sponsorship for 2021</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/09/noble-marine-insurance-renew-their-sponsorship-for-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Noble Marine Insurance renew their sponsorship for 2021" /><published>2021-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/09/noble-marine-insurance-renew-their-sponsorship-for-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/09/noble-marine-insurance-renew-their-sponsorship-for-2021/">&lt;p&gt;We’re extremely pleased to announce that  Noble Marine Insurance have renewed their sponsorship of the 2000 Class for 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noble have been impressed by the manner in which we can put their insurance expertise in front of our 280 + members by our Fast News emails, the 600 to 2000 people who regularly see our social media activity on Facebook and Instagram, the 70 + 2000 Fleet Captains at sailing clubs all over the 4 nations of the UK who can reach their 2000 club sailors, many of whom are not yet class association members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2000 Class sailors have always found insuring with Noble to be a truly painless experience; their premiums are usually the best and they give our members a very useful discount in addition. Noble’s claims handling is friendly , professional, quick and even sympathetic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noblemarine.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.noblemarine.co.uk/&quot;&gt;https://www.noblemarine.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/01/09/20190813_193654.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brace of Lauras toast Noble Marine Insurance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura Holmes - Short (L) &amp;amp;  Laura Barnham (R)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien, 2000 Class chair. </name></author><summary type="html">We’re extremely pleased to announce that Noble Marine Insurance have renewed their sponsorship of the 2000 Class for 2021.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are your sail numbers displayed legally?</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/02/are-your-sail-numbers-displayed-legally/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are your sail numbers displayed legally?" /><published>2021-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/02/are-your-sail-numbers-displayed-legally</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2021/01/02/are-your-sail-numbers-displayed-legally/">&lt;p&gt;Sail Numbers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear 2000 sailors, my name is John Best. I have been the technical Officer for the class for the last couple of years since my predecessor Richard decided to step over to the dark side and now sails a 400, quite successfully as I understand it. I have been messing about in boats since I was 8 which seems to be 64 years. 18 years ago I bought an RS 800, as my first asymmetric racing dinghy, then 15 years ago I bought 2000 2248, which made much more sense, and immediately disappeared to a SW France lake to sail it. It all came as a bit of a shock when I returned to the UK about 3 years ago, towing my trusty 2000 Mercury Rising behind me, and straight away sailed in the Castle Combe Nationals, only for two days and I had some new sails delivered to me at Castle Combe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked with complex sailing rules in various classes and about 22 years ago suddenly found myself in the role of an ISAF class measurer for Dragon’s and Flying Dutchman, both these classes are from the past but are still sailed all around the World. I do have some understanding of the closed class rules of the 2000 class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a much younger partner in crime, named Joe Gallivan, a young but experienced dinghy sailor, who came up through the Laser, RS Aero, RS 800, and latterly RS 700, he is in the market for a 2000, but has a great understanding of closed class rules and has agreed to cuff me round the ear if I behave badly with class rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are producing a series of articles about the 2000 rules, and we are going to start with Sail Numbers on the Mainsail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Too easy”, I hear you cry , I shan’t even need to read it , however, we have photographic evidence that about 25% of racing 2000’s have incorrectly laid out and stuck on sail numbers. “Why should I care” I hear you cry, but since I became the class technical chap two years ago, I have made a habit of talking to the Race Officers at the Nationals in Torquay and Tenby and they both said, “why haven’t all the boats got their numbers in the same place on their mainsails”! I wasn’t at the Brixham Nationals, put together by some very determined class members and Brixham Yacht Club, but the Race Officer there said much the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the closed rules are pretty specific about where the numbers should be, and we, Joe and I will gently remind you. If you haven’t already got a set of the 2000 class rules, there is a wealth of information in there, including what to do with sail numbers on your shiny new mainsail. The diagram, which is pretty self-explanatory can be found on page 4 of the measurement rules and was last edited in April 2019, so pretty recently! If you don’t feel the need to download the rules, or at least read them, ask yourself a question, “would I drive a vehicle without a perusal of the Highway Code”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/01/02/sail-number-measurement-rules.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sail numbers are an important part of a dinghy while racing due to being the easiest way of identifying a boat while out on the water. When racing is such big fleets (30+ boats) it can be difficult to spot when a boat is over the line and sail numbers helps them to be recorded for a disqualification. If the race officer or any of the race management cannot read the sail numbers due to incorrect fitting or placement, then this may give that competitor an unfair advantage and could lead to protests or even disqualification from the event for not complying with the class rules. These things are all avoided by making sure you sail, and boat comply with these rules to make sure the racing is fair between all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers should obviously be on the mainsail, starting or finishing 76 mm from the leech tape, each number should be 66 mm from the next one to it, and the numbers should be laid parallel to and 76 mm above or below the second mainsail batten, counting up from the mainsail foot. Starboard side numbers above the batten pocket and Port side numbers below it. When your shiny new mainsail turns up, and it may well be Charcoal coloured, you’ll know what to do, and the class has decided to stick with black numbers for the new mainsail fabric. We have included in the article the class rules page on sail numbers with diagrams on how they should be done correctly and also a photo of how they should look on a sail done correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2021/01/02/correct-sail-numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may not be aware of RS Boats and Hyde Sails decision, after consultation with us, the class managers, to not produce anymore white Aramid sailcloth, because it turns out that we are the only class using it, and are running out of it, when I spoke with Hyde sails after the first lockdown, they thought that they had enough for 8 more mainsails! They sold me the new concept by saying that only making about 2000 linear metres of white cloth would hike the price of the cloth by about 45%! Thus, we will soon be using a black see-through aramid shiny new material for mainsails, which my crew thinks is quite sexy, and a bit OO7ish! Amazingly enough the black sail numbers work quite well on it, better even than white ones, go figure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I actually find the black cloth easier to read! As another aside, if anybody has any queries about this new cloth or other measurement questions, we will, with the assistance of the class internet guru’s, attempt to set up an internet assistance address for rule queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to email us with any questions and wanting advice on anything 2000 based, our email address is &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tech@2000class.org&quot;&gt;tech@2000class.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Best and Joe Gallivan, Technical Chappies&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John Best &amp; Joe Gallivan , Technical Officers </name></author><summary type="html">Sail Numbers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series 2021 sponsorship details announced.</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2020/12/21/west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-2021-sponsorship-details-announced/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Country Boat Repairs Millennium Series 2021 sponsorship details announced." /><published>2020-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2020/12/21/west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-2021-sponsorship-details-announced</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2020/12/21/west-country-boat-repairs-millennium-series-2021-sponsorship-details-announced/">&lt;p&gt;Title Sponsor announced for the 2000 Class Millennium Series in 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;West Country Boat Repairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2000 Class have engaged with West Country Boat Repairs as their title sponsor for the 6 rounds of the Millennium Series in 2021. The Series will be 2 inland events and 4 sea rounds all in spectacular locations from Derbyshire in April down to Hampshire from April to September. In keeping with the ethos of the 2000s as friendly and serious racing in a boat that has everything the keen racer wants yet isn’t intimidating to the less experienced sailor, the programme next year gives opportunities for first time Open Event travellers at a large range of locations and in conditions likely to be manageable for the family sailors and sometimes challenging for the proficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“West Country Boat Repairs are delighted to be sponsoring the prestigious Millennium Series in 2021. We will be supplying a range of prizes including places on our Dinghy Repair workshops, a full 2000 refurbishment and plenty of our famous Ugly Mugs. We will have spot prizes as well as prizes for the overall winners, so there is a chance for everyone, whatever your level. We already know many of the 2000 sailors as valued customers and look forward to meeting the rest of the fleet during 2021. We know that there’s going to be at least one of the events that suits your location and experience so come and join in the fun; you may go home with a prize!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Millennium Series was taken in 2019 and 2020 by Simon Horsfield and Katie Burridge, the Sail Juice 2019 - 20 winners who’ve made a great start in the 20 -21 series, so the Millennium Series proves to be a great place to learn how to mix it with the top sailors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prizes available from West Country Boat Repairs include boat and foils overhauls, and days on WCBR’s boat repair courses at their workshops in Gloucestershire. There are also places on racing sailing training courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a great fit for the 2000 Class “said Mark Foley, 2000 Publicity Officer. “We are constantly dealing with people asking us where they can get their hands on a 2000, as they are snapped up when they come up for sale. So what better way to look after your boat’s resale value than get an upgrade courtesy of WCBR, or spend a day on a course learning how to keep your boat in tip top condition by yourself? Indeed, if you are not in the position to get a new boat from RS Sailing, when you see a boat for sale that needs some work, put yourself in touch with WCBR beforehand and have a chat about what the improvements you want might cost before you negotiate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below: Mark Foley 2000 Class publicity &amp;amp; Pete Vincent of West Country Boat Repairs, enjoying one of their boat repair courses in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/12/25/2020-06-23_6546.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Foley, 2000 Class publicity.  </name></author><summary type="html">Title Sponsor announced for the 2000 Class Millennium Series in 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Events Programme published</title><link href="https://www.2000class.org/2020/11/30/2021-events-programme-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Events Programme published" /><published>2020-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.2000class.org/2020/11/30/2021-events-programme-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.2000class.org/2020/11/30/2021-events-programme-published/">&lt;p&gt;Rob Burridge has finalised the 2021 events programme encompassing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Millennium Open Series&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Northern Series&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Coached Open meetings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*National Championships&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All events are now detailed on the Events page. Check them out and start pencilling in the ones you want to do, assuming you can’t make them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/11/30/_dsc8247-edit-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Foley </name></author><summary type="html">Rob Burridge has finalised the 2021 events programme encompassing</summary></entry></feed>