<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_GB" /><updated>2020-11-21T16:23:05-06:00</updated><id>https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">2000 Class Association</title><subtitle>The 2000 Class Association is the official association for the 2000 sailing  dinghy. The 2000, previously known as the Laser 2000, is an entry-level  performance assymmetric sailing dinghy. The boat is sailed by serious racers and families alike.
</subtitle><author><name>2000 Class Association</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Lockdown Upwind Downwind Challenge</title><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/06/01/the-lockdown-upwind-downwind-challenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Lockdown Upwind Downwind Challenge" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/06/01/the-lockdown-upwind-downwind-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/06/01/the-lockdown-upwind-downwind-challenge.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/06/01/screenshot-2020-06-01-at-12-46-35.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Try this race on Sunday: The Lockdown Upwind Downwind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can sail your 2000 on Sunday try this distance race against all your other 2000 Friends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current restrictions mean that traditional open meetings have had to be cancelled, and club racing is severely curtailed.&lt;br /&gt;
The 2000 Class Association would like to introduce the ‘2000 distance event’.&lt;br /&gt;
This is a real sailing event, and we hope more and more people can join in as clubs and water areas gradually open.&lt;br /&gt;
The ‘event’ can be undertaken at any location, and at any time each Sunday.&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly this means that the varying weather across the UK may well have a major impact on the results, but in these strange times, it is good to just be on the water.&lt;br /&gt;
2000 distance event&lt;br /&gt;
1. A windward/leeward course must be sailed.&lt;br /&gt;
2. The course can be any length, as long as it comprises one windward and one leeward mark. At least one windward and one leeward leg must be completed within the 45 minute period.&lt;br /&gt;
3. Sailors are to record the distance sailed in 45 minutes while sailing the windward/leeward course.&lt;br /&gt;
4. Send helm/crew info, plus boat number and club, along with the distance sailed, and a screenshot of a GPS track (to prove the course and distance). Send to sailsec@2000class.org by 1800 on the Monday after sailing.&lt;br /&gt;
5. GPS tracks can be created by any GPS watch or smartphone system as long as it shows the 45 minute time and the distance sailed, along with a track.&lt;br /&gt;
6. The 45 minute period can be repeated as many times as you wish, but the track submitted must be a continuous 45 minute period.&lt;br /&gt;
Who will get the furthest distance at your club, or in your area, or across the country?&lt;br /&gt;
Join in for some 2000 fun while we await more traditional events in the future.&lt;br /&gt;
Important; Ensure that you comply with all Government, National, and club, guidelines and restrictions when taking part in this ‘event’.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien (Chair)</name></author><summary type="html">Try this race on Sunday: The Lockdown Upwind Downwind</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Update 2020 UK Nationals - Brixham YC 16th - 21st August 20</title><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/05/09/update-2020-uk-nationals-brixham-yc-16th-21st-august-20.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update 2020 UK Nationals - Brixham YC 16th - 21st August 20" /><published>2020-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/05/09/update-2020-uk-nationals-brixham-yc-16th-21st-august-20</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/05/09/update-2020-uk-nationals-brixham-yc-16th-21st-august-20.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020 UK National Championships - Brixham YC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 - 21st August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/05/09/Screenshot 2020-05-09 at 14.15.20.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29th April 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had the following update from Brixham YC regarding the Nationals and the Covid-19 situation:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Assuming the current restrictions are lifted, we will definitely help where we can with the social distancing, catering etc. Our chef Lee has continued working through the crisis providing delivery and take away to members. He has proven nothing will stop him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. We are very much following the RYA guidance at the moment in terms of events, training etc. Their current guidance is that events should be cancelled until at least 31st May. We will let you know if and when their guidance changes or the club makes any further decisions. We are all fully committed to getting the club back to running events and getting people back out onto the water as soon as we safely can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. With regards to local accommodation, most are still taking bookings from June onwards with the obvious disclaimer that restrictions may not be lifted by the government. Have checked the Century Road campsite and they are taking bookings for the period but also showing a low availability. The Quayside Hotels seem to have quite a few rooms available for the period, the berry head hotel responding to email only at the moment. We have a list of local accommodation here:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brixhamyachtclub.com/info-m&quot; title=&quot;https://www.brixhamyachtclub.com/info-m&quot;&gt;https://www.brixhamyachtclub.com/info-m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brixhamyachtclub.com/info-membership/local-accommodation?fbclid=IwAR33gsL9QaAFDHDAepY3q8FBpLmTshwq6HPzPRWFXAKaWEwQlanWsYZyomU&quot;&gt;…/local-accommodation&lt;/a&gt; if your members wish to enquire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLEASE NOTE that the 2020 Nationals at Brixham are restricted to just 70 boats and as at 25 February 2020 we have 40 entries confirmed so don’t delay your entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you later decide you have to vacate your place it is possible another boat will substitute for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kev Obi (Chair)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien (Chair)</name></author><summary type="html">Update</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boat Speed with Simon Horsfield - Friday 1st May 20</title><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/30/boat-speed-with-simon-horsfield-friday-1st-may-20.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boat Speed with Simon Horsfield - Friday 1st May 20" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/30/boat-speed-with-simon-horsfield-friday-1st-may-20</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/30/boat-speed-with-simon-horsfield-friday-1st-may-20.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/04/30/Screenshot 2020-04-30 at 16.19.24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/04/30/Screenshot 2020-04-30 at 16.26.21.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000 Boat Speed ‘Zoom’ Online Training Session&lt;/strong&gt; with National Champion &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonhorsfieldcoaching.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Simon Horsfield&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High demand for this session; don’t miss out !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MayDay Zoom training session on the topic of Boat Speed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Light winds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• High winds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Downwind modes of sailing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join from 7.00pm for a 7.30pm start on Friday 1st May&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No limit on numbers for this event, but Class Association members only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To book email Zoom Master Helen accounts@2000class.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Zoom here &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoom.us/&quot; title=&quot;https://zoom.us/&quot;&gt;https://zoom.us/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Simon Says……&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never Be Late For The Start&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2000 Class Association - Lockdown Quiz Two!</title><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/30/2000-class-association-lockdown-quiz-two.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2000 Class Association - Lockdown Quiz Two!" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/30/2000-class-association-lockdown-quiz-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/30/2000-class-association-lockdown-quiz-two.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000 Class Association - Lockdown Quiz Two! &lt;br /&gt;
Friday 8th May 20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/04/30/Screenshot 2020-04-17 at 19.15.23.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Lockdown Quiz Two !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staunton Harold is missing us on 9-10 May so instead join your 2000 friends on Zoom for the &lt;br /&gt;
Staunton Harold SC Replacement Service :: Lockdown Quiz Two !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday 8th May &lt;br /&gt;
7.00pm for a 7.30pm start&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25 questions, so make sure you have nibbles and drinks ready for a good 2 hours..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limited to 20 Zoom participants and only Class Association members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enter email Zoom Master Helen &lt;a href=&quot;Lockdown Quiz Two !     Staunton Harold is missing us on 9-10 May so instead join your 2000 friends on Zoom for the  Staunton Harold SC Replacement Service :: Lockdown Quiz Two !  Friday 8th May  7.00pm for a 7.30pm start  25 questions, so make sure you have nibbles and drinks ready for a good 2 hours..  Limited to 20 Zoom participants and only Class Association members.   To enter email Zoom Master Helen accounts@2000class.org&quot;&gt;accounts@2000class.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kev O'Brien</name></author><summary type="html">2000 Class Association - Lockdown Quiz Two! Friday 8th May 20</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2000 Class Training has been postponed until July 2020</title><link href="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/17/2000-class-training-has-been-postponed-until-july-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2000 Class Training has been postponed until July 2020" /><published>2020-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/17/2000-class-training-has-been-postponed-until-july-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://2000class.unifiedtechnicalsolutions.co.uk/2020/04/17/2000-class-training-has-been-postponed-until-july-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/04/17/Screenshot 2020-04-17 at 16.37.48.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noblemarine.co.uk/home.php3?ad=6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noble Marine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;supported 2000 Class Training is has been postponed until 4th-5th July, when we hope social distancing will allow it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The double &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seldenmast.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Selden&lt;/a&gt; SailJuice Winter Series Champions Simon Horsfield and Katie Burridge are delivering the weekend at Thorney Island Sailing Club, aided and abetted by several of the class’s top sailors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend format will include starting, dynamic tuning, modes of downwind sailing, and short course racing, backed up with video debriefing. 23 boats were due to take part in April and we’re hoping they can all still make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2000 Class is renowned for attracting a wide demographic of sailors, and this event is just like that; ages range from 14 to 75 years old, and abilities range from champions to open meeting novices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendance at class events has grown quickly over the past two years, boosted by two innovations; a committee member whose role is purely publicity, and a focus of developing sailing skills by informal and formal training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So would you like 2000 training at your club? If you have a small fleet of 2000s at your club or in your area, why not get in touch with a view to 2021? Please contact the class at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sailsec@2000class.org&quot;&gt;sailsec@2000class.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So have a look on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/2000classassociation/&quot;&gt;our class Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; and you’ll see some Top Tips videos by the front of the fleet sailors, come to any event and you’ll get more boat park and on-course advice than you know what to do with, and feel free to ask anyone any question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also making the most of having Simon Horsfield sailing in our ranks. He is a professional British Army dinghy coach and amateur dinghy racer who has competed in the 2000 Class since 2006. Simon says: “On the face of it, it is such a simple boat, and yet I believe that’s what makes it such a challenge to get the maximum performance out of the 2000. 13 years in, and I’m still finding new ways of making it go faster, and that’s having been at the front of the fleet for many years and National Champion in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As the Training Officer for our class I want to share my knowledge and experience with the whole fleet by running specific and bespoke training, tailored to you. One of the class’s main assets is that it attracts a huge variety of ages and abilities, requiring this tailored training.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon is leaving the Army in May 2022, and working as a coach will be part of his future plans, so if you’d like to discuss non-2000 Class topics, get in touch at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:simonhorsfield76@gmail.com&quot;&gt;simonhorsfield76@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile he and fiancée/crew Katie Burridge have been keeping fit for the 2020 season with daily running and high intensity interval training.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Foley</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>